<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSist</title>
    <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CSist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us-vi</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:49:40 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiennvcs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing task I: Time-based chart</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_i_based-time_chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:49:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_i_based-time_chart/</guid>
      <description>To begin with, in writing task I in the IELTS exam, we start with dealing with basic question types: given a chart whose figures change over time and our mission is to summarize the information and make relevant comparisons.
Question, outline, and essential sentence structures  You should spend about 20 minutes on this task.
The graph and table below show the average carbon dioxide ($\text{CO}_\text{2}$) emissions per person in the United Kingdom, Sweden, Italy, and Portugal between 1967 and 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing task II: Practice exercise 2</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_sentence_translate_practice_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 23:51:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_sentence_translate_practice_2/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s practice these questions for more better in writing task II.
Questions   Bạo động vũ trang có thể kích động những phần tử xấu trong xã hội và gây ra những bất ổn không thể cứu chữa.   Những đứa trẻ bị ghẻ lạnh có thể bỏ nhà ra đi mà sẽ dẫn chúng đến một tương lai mịt mù.   Những người phải gánh chịu tình yêu đơn phương sẽ cảm thấy thất vọng bởi vì họ nghĩ rằng họ không thể tìm thấy một mối tình tương xứng nào nữa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing task II: Practice exercise</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_sentence_translate_practice_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 17:56:20 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_sentence_translate_practice_1/</guid>
      <description>It is easy to think about a complete sentence in your mother tone language but we need to grammatically correctly write English sentences in our essay in writing task II. These practical exercises in this post will enhance our phraseology to be more formal.
Questions   Những con robot có thể giúp con người làm việc nhà một cách hiệu quả và nhanh chóng nhằm giúp con người có thêm thời gian cho những sở thích cá nhân.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Task II - Discuss both views and give your opinion</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/wriing_task_ii_discuss_both_views_opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 23:13:59 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/wriing_task_ii_discuss_both_views_opinion/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Discuss both views and give your own opinion&amp;rdquo; is one of the important question types in writing task II. This post aims to give step-by-step to tackle this issue.
Question and outline  Writing task II
Some people think that it&amp;rsquo;s important to spend money on family celebrations (e.g., weddings, birthdays). But something expensive celebrations are a waste of money. Discuss both views and give your opinion.
There are two opposing beliefs given in the question:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Task II - Agree/Disagree: Increasing road safety based on increasing the minimum legal age for driving cars or riding motorbikes.</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_argree_disagree_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 01:21:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_argree_disagree_2/</guid>
      <description>This post continually shows an agree/disagree question type in Writing task II.
Question and outline Question
Some people think that the best way to increase road safety is to increase the minimum legal age for driving cars or riding motorbikes. Do you agree or disagree with this belief?
Outline
 Agree $\rightarrow$ write the introduction: One of the most controversial issues today relates to the approval of increasing the minimum legal age for driving cars or riding motorbikes in order to ensure road safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Task II: Agree/disagree 🥵</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_agree_disagree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 16:40:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_agree_disagree/</guid>
      <description>In IELTS writing task II, you are given a topic and your mission is to write an essay discussing it, and the total length of your answer should be at least 250 words.
Example and step-by-step to complete this task  Suppose you are dealing with the IELTS writing task II below.
Task 2. Some people believe that governments should pay full course fees for students who want to study at universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IELTS: An overview</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/introduction_to_ielts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:58:18 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/introduction_to_ielts/</guid>
      <description>When I started to apply to a graduate program, I got stuck with the English certificate requirement. Currently, I am studying for IELTS and being prepared for the upcoming exam so I think one of the best ways to learn is by sharing. So in this sector, I write anything I learned. Of course, I hope it will be good material for you if you are the one also concerned about IELTS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tien Nguyen</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 14:00:05 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Educations  2018-2022 B.S. Honor program in Computer Science from Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City - University of Information Technology(VNUHCM-UIT).
Publications  2021 M. Tran, T. Pham, T. Nguyen, T. Do and T. N. Duc, &amp;ldquo;A robust framework for mathematical formula detection,&amp;rdquo; 2021 International Conference on Multimedia Analysis and Pattern Recognition (MAPR), 2021, pp. 1-6, doi: 10.1109/MAPR53640.2021.9585197.
Vietnamese Patent  2022 Trien Thai, T. Nguyen, Tuan Nguyen. 2022. Phương pháp xác định vị trí tàu biển gặp nạn (English title: Detecting the ship in distress based on optical satellite images and automatic identity system signal).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:56:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description>2022   Evaluate some deep learning methods for infographic visual question answering. (Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis) code | report  2021   Estimate solutions of system of non-linear equations using Newton Raphson.
code | report Instance search in image using DEep Local Features (DELF) code | report  2020   Detect failing bottle caps from industrial camera stream. code | report Object detection implementation using Yolo and Capsule Network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>