<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Think like Computer Scientist</title>
    <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Think like Computer Scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us-vi</language><atom:link href="https://tiennvcs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 14:00:05 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Educations B.S. Honor program in Computer Science from Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City - University of Information Technology(VNUHCM-UIT) (2018-2022). Experiences AI research engineer at Viettel High Technology Industries Corporation (VHT), Vietnam (3/2022-current). Teacher assistant in at University of Information Technology(VNUHCM-UIT) (11/2021-3/2022). Research practitioner at University of Information Technology(VNUHCM-UIT) (2019-2022). Miscellaneous My CV is available at here. In three continous years (2019, 2020, 2021), I got &amp;ldquo;Student of 5 merits&amp;rdquo; achievement by the University of Information Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/public/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:58:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/public/</guid>
      <description>Conferences 2021 M. Tran, T. Pham, T. Nguyen, T. Do and T. N. Duc, &amp;ldquo;A robust framework for mathematical formula detection,&amp;rdquo; 2021 International Conference on Multimedia Analysis and Pattern Recognition (MAPR), 2021, pp. 1-6, doi: 10.1109/MAPR53640.2021.9585197.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:56:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description>2022 Evaluate some deep learning methods for infographic visual question answering. (Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis) code | report 2021 Estimate solutions of system of non-linear equations using Newton Raphson.
code | report Instance search in image using DEep Local Features (DELF) code | report 2020 Detect failing bottle caps from stream camera video in industry. code | report Object detection implementation using Yolo and Capsule Network.
code | report Comparing compression algorithm on text data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>