<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSist</title>
    <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CSist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us-vi</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 16:40:50 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiennvcs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing Task II: Agree/disagree 🥵</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_agree_disagree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 16:40:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/writing_task_ii_agree_disagree/</guid>
      <description>In IELTS writing task II, you are given a topic and your mission is to write an essay discussing it, and the total length of your answer should be at least 250 words.
Example and step-by-step to complete this task  Suppose you are dealing with the IELTS writing task II below.
Task 2. Some people believe that governments should pay full course fees for students who want to study at universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IELTS: An overview</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/introduction_to_ielts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:58:18 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/ielts/introduction_to_ielts/</guid>
      <description>When I started to apply to a graduate program, I got stuck with the English certificate requirement. Currently, I am studying for IELTS and being prepared for the upcoming exam so I think one of the best ways to learn is by sharing. So in this sector, I write anything I learned. Of course, I hope it will be good material for you if you are the one also concerned about IELTS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 14:00:05 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Educations  2018-2022 B.S. Honor program in Computer Science from Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City - University of Information Technology(VNUHCM-UIT).
Publications  2021 M. Tran, T. Pham, T. Nguyen, T. Do and T. N. Duc, &amp;ldquo;A robust framework for mathematical formula detection,&amp;rdquo; 2021 International Conference on Multimedia Analysis and Pattern Recognition (MAPR), 2021, pp. 1-6, doi: 10.1109/MAPR53640.2021.9585197.
Vietnamese Patent  2022 Trien Thai, T. Nguyen, Tuan Nguyen. 2022. Phương pháp xác định vị trí tàu biển gặp nạn (English title: Detecting the ship in distress based on optical satellite images and automatic identity system signal).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>https://tiennvcs.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:56:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiennvcs.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description>2022   Evaluate some deep learning methods for infographic visual question answering. (Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis) code | report  2021   Estimate solutions of system of non-linear equations using Newton Raphson.
code | report Instance search in image using DEep Local Features (DELF) code | report  2020   Detect failing bottle caps from stream camera video in industry. code | report Object detection implementation using Yolo and Capsule Network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>